<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/feed/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://bitworking.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-26T02:15:07-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/</id><title type="html">BitWorking</title><subtitle>Joe Gregorio - REST, Web, Python, Go, APIs, Dad, Husband, Maker, or any linear combination of such. Googler.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A thing that happened</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thing that happened" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T02:14:48-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened">&lt;p&gt;So here I am on a Tuesday morning, in the bathroom, getting ready for work
while my wife still sleeps. The only context you need for what’s about to
happen next is that my intestines had been a little sore the previous two
days and that last year I found out that I had diverticulosis. The latter
found because when you turn 50 you get a free colonoscopy. I really don’t
think there is a more apt metaphor for turning 50 than a free colonoscopy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;, the rest of this story contains references to urine, feces,
blood, needles, and any number of other unpleasant dinner table topics. If
you are squeamish, or would be unable to look me in the eye the next time we
meet, you should stop reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sitting on the toilet when I get a huge flapping and stabbing pain in my
intestines. This is a pain that is so intense and otherworldly that I’m thrown
off the toilet onto my hands and knees. It is hard to describe this feeling,
but imagine taking a wooden children’s block, you know the ones, with the big
letters and numbers on them in bold colors? So take one of those, attach it to
the head of a 3/8” drill-bit, shove that up your ass, and then turn on the
drill. Yeah, that’s exactly what it felt like. I’m able to crawl a few
feet before calling out to my wife, where she finds me naked in the fetal
position on the cold bathroom tile floor. She asks, and as I can start to
breath again as the pain descends, on a scale from 0 to 10, from a 10 down to
about a 6, I explain what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s start with getting me a pillow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lying on the floor for awhile and having the pain subside down to about
a 4, I get dressed, and get a 2pm doctor’s appointment. The office says they
can and do want to see me soon given the severity of what might be going on,
so I schedule a 2pm appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never make that appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynne is out walking the dog, almost back to the house, when I call her,
“Forget the doctor’s appointment, we need to go to the ER, now!” My pain has
shot back up to an 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pain for next two hours will oscillate between a 4 and an 8. Yes, you heard
that correctly, the next two hours. It will take that long to get me though
the triaging process and into an ER bed and enough tests run that they start
to give me something for the pain. I do get the idea that the doctors don’t
want to mask any pain that might help with a diagnosis, but do you really
think that the difference between me howling incoherently and merely able to
speak and tell them my pain is a 6 is that sharp of a diagnostic tool?
Regardless, I spend the next two hours oscillating between a 4 and an 8, and
anything above a 7 requires chanting the “Litany of Pain”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Shit. Fuck. Damn.”
“Shit. Fuck. Damn.”
“Fuck. Fuck. Fucking fuckity fuck.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I promptly did, for an hour, in the ER waiting room lying across a bench
seat. Please note that I understand that your personal “Litany of Pain” may differ,
and may change based on the pain level, for example mine tends to peter out at
a 9 to just gurgling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CT scan comes back with “inflamed diverticulum” and a surgeon appears to
explain that given my pain it’s probably ruptured and that she’d like to
operate, or we could wait awhile and see if antibiotics make a difference in
the pain. I’m not going to jump into any surgery, so I decide to wait, but the
description of what the actual surgery will entail really makes me uneasy. The
plan would be open me up, cut out the offending piece of colon, and route the
end of the now shorter colon into an ostomy. I had no idea the human body was
that flexible, “Hey let’s re-route your butt hole to somewhere in your
abdomen!” seems more like a Zoidberg surgery than an actual procedure, who
knew? Anyway, then the rest of the plan is to wait three months for everything
to heal, and do the reverse surgery, undoing the colonostomy and reconnecting
my colon to my anus. What exactly my anus is supposed to be doing for those
three months is a question I forget to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend the next 24 hours in the hospital with IV antibiotics as my
temperature, white blood cell count, and pain continue to rise. A new CT scan
confirms that I have a ruptured colon: I will not be avoiding surgery. In
fact, they are so alarmed that they take me straight from the CT to the
operating room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about “Versed”, a drug that they give you before surgery so that
you don’t remember any of the horrors that surgery, or surgery prep, or coming
out of surgery entail. It does all that, but apparently it also pretty well
scrambles your brain for some time following the surgery. When I woke up in my
hospital room the doctor was there explaining my status, the surgery, what
they found, and next steps to my wife. Except that my brain was translating
their entire conversation into Kubernetes command line strings (essentially a
kind of programming language). And I’m there taking in as if was completely
normal, like I’m happy I got the surgery at such a cutting edge place that
they’re using Kubernetes to control their surgical procedures. It’s not until
days later in the hospital, in a fleeting instance of lucidity, that I realize
how fucking insane and nonsensical that sounds. So I begin going back over
the things I know and fact checking them. I know, for example, that they have
me up and walking right after surgery and that I take regular walks on that
hospital floor, and as I get better I might be able to go for a walk in the
outside exercise area, which is a small stone lined plaza in Italy. Wait,
what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the full eight days I spent in the hospital are a little
fuzzy, and I might not be an accurate witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the eight days I had get to past certain milestones, such as peeing on my
own. I never realized how happy you could make a nurse by peeing, which
apparently comes in second place only to how happy you can make a nurse by
producing stool from your stoma. I’m pretty sure I was an infant the last time
that many people were excited by my poop production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am home recovering from colon surgery. It’s like having a new baby, all
the conversations are about pee, poop, and sleeping schedules, except in this
case I’m the baby. Really it’s all about the gas. Every part of my now
shortened digestive tract is swollen and irritable, so everything produces
gas, and all gas produces discomfort. Which leads me to my three rules of
colon surgery recovery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s always gas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walking fixes everything. (See #1).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unless maybe you’re hungry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I walk, and I walk, and I walk. In the house though, because it has been
either too cold outside, or drenching rain. So I walk up and down the upstairs
hall, or loop-de-loops around the furniture downstairs, and I belch, and I
belch, and I belch. That’s apparently yet another thing that makes nurses
happy; I would doing one of my regular walks in the hospital wing and let out
one of those deep, loud belches that start at your toes, and a cheer would
rise from the nurses station every time. Nurses are weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just two days home from the hospital at this point, with another two weeks
of recovery at least before I can return to anything resembling a normal life,
except for the shadow of the reversal surgery hanging out there three months from now.
Thanks for reading this far, if anyone has. I know that writing it has
certainly helped me process the adventure so far. Many thanks to friends and
family for all their support, it means a huge amount to me and Lynne. Oh yeah,
did I mention that Lynne had a sinus infection through all this, she’s been
an amazing trooper, my rock, and I wouldn’t have made it through without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">So here I am on a Tuesday morning, in the bathroom, getting ready for work while my wife still sleeps. The only context you need for what’s about to happen next is that my intestines had been a little sore the previous two days and that last year I found out that I had diverticulosis. The latter found because when you turn 50 you get a free colonoscopy. I really don’t think there is a more apt metaphor for turning 50 than a free colonoscopy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nine steps for Facebook</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nine steps for Facebook" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T16:37:58-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/22/restructure-facebook-ftc-regulate-9-steps-now&quot;&gt;Facebook must be restructured. The FTC should take these nine steps now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was published back in March of 2018, but it’s still a good list of things
that should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Facebook must be restructured. The FTC should take these nine steps now</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Make Me Smart Question</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/the-make-me-smart-question" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Make Me Smart Question" /><published>2018-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-26T08:33:25-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/the-make-me-smart-question</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/the-make-me-smart-question">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketplace.org/topics/make-me-smart&quot;&gt;Make Me Smart&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast
with co-hosts Kai Ryssdal and Molly Wood. One of the features of the show is
asking both guests and listeners the “Make Me Smart Question”, which is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is something you thought you knew, but later found out you were wrong
about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the final episode of the year, my answer got selected! It starts at minute 33 of the podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.marketplace.org/2018/12/18/business/make-me-smart-kai-and-molly/95-our-predictions-2019/popout&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;240px&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Make Me Smart is a podcast with co-hosts Kai Ryssdal and Molly Wood. One of the features of the show is asking both guests and listeners the “Make Me Smart Question”, which is:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guidelines for creating web platform compatible components</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/guidelines-for-creating-web-platform-compatible-components" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guidelines for creating web platform compatible components" /><published>2018-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-26T09:28:53-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/guidelines-for-creating-web-platform-compatible-components</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/guidelines-for-creating-web-platform-compatible-components">&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&quot;https://infrequently.org/2018/12/alice-boxhall-for-w3c-tag/&quot;&gt;Alex Russell&lt;/a&gt;, I just found
&lt;a href=&quot;https://w3ctag.github.io/webcomponents-design-guidelines/&quot;&gt;Guidelines for creating web platform compatible components&lt;/a&gt;,
which further contains a link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/webcomponents/gold-standard/wiki&quot;&gt;The Gold Standard Checklist for Web Components&lt;/a&gt;,
both of which look like excellent resources when creating custom elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good time to mention that work is progressing on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/elements-sk&quot;&gt;elements-sk&lt;/a&gt;, a set of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitworking.org/news/2018/02/custom-elements-neat&quot;&gt;neat&lt;/a&gt; Vanilla JS
custom elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Via Alex Russell, I just found Guidelines for creating web platform compatible components, which further contains a link to The Gold Standard Checklist for Web Components, both of which look like excellent resources when creating custom elements.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alone in the White House</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/alone-in-the-white-house" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alone in the White House" /><published>2018-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-26T08:50:06-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/alone-in-the-white-house</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/alone-in-the-white-house">&lt;p&gt;From June of 2017, this Tweet has aged like a fine wine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;He eventually fires everyone. Just him, alone, on Twitter, in the WH. And the person that brings him his soda, that person never gets fired. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/eVISOqQw5i&quot;&gt;https://t.co/eVISOqQw5i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Joe Gregorio (@bitworking) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bitworking/status/871912124595007490?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">From June of 2017, this Tweet has aged like a fine wine:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meritocracy</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/meritocracy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meritocracy" /><published>2018-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-17T23:04:27-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/meritocracy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/meritocracy">&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meritocracy&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    A system in which venture capitalists give large sums of money to
    20-something male Stanford graduates in computer science.
  &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Meritocracy A system in which venture capitalists give large sums of money to 20-something male Stanford graduates in computer science.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prometheus alerts and missing data</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/prometheus-alerts-and-missing-data" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prometheus alerts and missing data" /><published>2018-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-15T10:17:23-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/prometheus-alerts-and-missing-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/prometheus-alerts-and-missing-data">&lt;p&gt;Alerting in &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io&quot;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt; is great, and easy, but one of
the gotchas is that there’s no warnings or errors if you write an alert rule
and there’s no data for that alert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Prometheus does have the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;absent()&lt;/code&gt; function, and you could tack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;OR absent(some_metric_name) == 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to the end of every alert you write, but that’s tedious and error prone.
So I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/skia-buildbot/blob/master/promk/go/promk-absent/main.go&quot;&gt;promk-absent&lt;/a&gt;
a quick little tool on Go to create a set of absence alerts based on
an existing set of alerts. It just processes a single alerts YAML file
and emits a new alerts YAML file with one absent alert for each alert
in the original file. To install it run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;go get go.skia.org/infra/promk/go/promk-absent
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then run it with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;promk-absent --input=your-rules.yml --output=absent-rules.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to include your new absent rules in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prometheus.yml&lt;/code&gt;
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool does have the restriction that all expressions must be written in
the form of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;expression relation constant
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so far that hasn’t been an issue for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Alerting in Prometheus is great, and easy, but one of the gotchas is that there’s no warnings or errors if you write an alert rule and there’s no data for that alert.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Core Slicing</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/core-slicing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Core Slicing" /><published>2018-12-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-12T12:13:50-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/core-slicing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/core-slicing">&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://meltdownattack.com/&quot;&gt;Spectre and Meltdown&lt;/a&gt; we can see the
inevitable results of trying to squeeze more and more performance out of a
small number of cores. I believe the future is in processors with a high
number of cores, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://riscv.org/&quot;&gt;RISC-V&lt;/a&gt;. With hundreds or
thousands of cores on a single chip you can stop doing time-slicing and start
doing core-slicing. That is, instead of doing preemtive multitasking, each
process will be scheduled with a subset of the total number of core. The cores
will be distrubuted among the processes that are running and they will keep
those cores until they are done. A change in priority for a process would mean
they get more or less cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">With Spectre and Meltdown we can see the inevitable results of trying to squeeze more and more performance out of a small number of cores. I believe the future is in processors with a high number of cores, such as RISC-V. With hundreds or thousands of cores on a single chip you can stop doing time-slicing and start doing core-slicing. That is, instead of doing preemtive multitasking, each process will be scheduled with a subset of the total number of core. The cores will be distrubuted among the processes that are running and they will keep those cores until they are done. A change in priority for a process would mean they get more or less cores.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hot Take</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/hot-take" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hot Take" /><published>2018-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-08T11:13:38-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/hot-take</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/12/hot-take">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few articles that are good background on what I am about to
talk about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/07/science/climate-change-mass-extinction.html&quot;&gt;The Planet Has Seen Sudden Warming Before. It Wiped Out Almost Everything.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/27/magazine/insect-apocalypse.html&quot;&gt;The Insect Apocalypse Is Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/11/06/climate/world-emissions-goals-far-off-course.html&quot;&gt;Here’s How Far the World Is From Meeting Its Climate Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, after watching climate change research for years and watching
the effects of climate change arrive faster than predicted, and the continual
shortening of timelines for climate change effects, and the fact that we are
nowhere close to cutting emissions fast enough, I firmly believe that climate
change is an existential threat to humans and that we need to start
researching geoengineering strategies for cooling the planet today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we still need to research fusion power and move as fast as possible to
wind, solar, and other renewable sources of power, but I don’t believe
that we can transition fast enough, and given that we are talking about the
lives of millions, if not billions, of humans on the line, it is morally
irresponsible to not research geoengineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Here are a few articles that are good background on what I am about to talk about:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oligopoly collusion</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/11/oligarchy-collusion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oligopoly collusion" /><published>2018-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-30T07:55:21-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2018/11/oligarchy-collusion</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2018/11/oligarchy-collusion">&lt;p&gt;Don’t you just love it when oligopolies collude?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p title=&quot;Alaska Airlines giving preferential treatment to Facebook and Apple.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/collusion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alaska Airlines giving preferential treatment to Facebook and Apple.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you were a small startup with a new idea for a chat application. How
could you ever compete with this? Is there any wonder there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/20/business/economy/startup-business.html&quot;&gt;startup
slump&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Don’t you just love it when oligopolies collude?</summary></entry></feed>