<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/feed/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://bitworking.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-04T08:52:22-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/</id><title type="html">BitWorking</title><subtitle>Joe Gregorio - REST, Web, Python, Go, APIs, Dad, Husband, Maker, or any linear combination of such. Googler.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CEO Pay</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/03/ceo-pay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CEO Pay" /><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T08:52:19-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/03/ceo-pay</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/03/ceo-pay">&lt;p&gt;I’ve said the Harvard MBA is the most second most damaging thing to happen to business in the last 40 years.
I might have to clarify that to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/b1db3jy3201d38/The-MBA-Myth-and-the-Cult-of-the-CEO&quot;&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;myth&lt;/strong&gt; of the Harvard MBA is the second
most damaging thing to happen to business in the last 40 years&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the first most damaging thing to happen to business in the past 40 years? &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2017/10/25/stiglitz-vs-friedman.html&quot;&gt;The Chicago School of Economics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve said the Harvard MBA is the most second most damaging thing to happen to business in the last 40 years. I might have to clarify that to “the myth of the Harvard MBA is the second most damaging thing to happen to business in the last 40 years”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arts and crafts</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/arts-and-crafts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arts and crafts" /><published>2019-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T10:15:30-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/arts-and-crafts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/arts-and-crafts">&lt;p&gt;When you have a stoma &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt; is arts and crafts day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swear I’ve modified more articles of clothing than my sister did
during her entire teenage life in the 80s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">When you have a stoma every day is arts and crafts day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">gcsfuse and systemd –user</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/gcsfuse-and-systemd-user" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="gcsfuse and systemd --user" /><published>2019-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T09:10:59-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/gcsfuse-and-systemd-user</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/gcsfuse-and-systemd-user">&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud Storage has an officially supported &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/gcs-fuse&quot;&gt;fuse client&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I have always wanted and would have expected for Google
Drive, but 🤷.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing better than a fuse client is a fuse directory that gets
mounted automatically when you log in, which you can do fairly simply
using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systemd --user&lt;/code&gt;, which is just systemd, but everthing runs as you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a gist of how I set this up on my machine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jcgregorio/3d30cb7673e80b85c2153db9ff8be7c4.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Google Cloud Storage has an officially supported fuse client!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google SRE Book and Workbook</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/google-sre-book-and-workbook" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google SRE Book and Workbook" /><published>2019-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-22T10:06:33-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/google-sre-book-and-workbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/google-sre-book-and-workbook">&lt;p&gt;I never realized the detail that the Google SRE book provided
&lt;a href=&quot;https://landing.google.com/sre/sre-book/chapters/production-environment/&quot;&gt;on the production environment at Google&lt;/a&gt;,
including such things as D, Colossus, Jupiter, BNS, and GSLB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there’s now &lt;a href=&quot;https://landing.google.com/sre/workbook/toc/&quot;&gt;The Site Reliability Workbook&lt;/a&gt;, a hands-on implementation guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">I never realized the detail that the Google SRE book provided on the production environment at Google, including such things as D, Colossus, Jupiter, BNS, and GSLB.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More TMI recovery stories</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/more-tmi-recovery-stories" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More TMI recovery stories" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T11:48:09-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/more-tmi-recovery-stories</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/more-tmi-recovery-stories">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is another story from my recovery that might be TMI for some people. Read with caution, or skip.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened&quot;&gt;while describing my initial hospitalization&lt;/a&gt;
I mentioned an open question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What exactly my anus is supposed to be doing for those three months is a question I forget to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I know from the questions and comments I’ve received that many of you
are curious too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer turns out to be “nothing much” for most of the time, with
occassional bouts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_limb&quot;&gt;Phantom Limb&lt;/a&gt; sensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the “phantom limb” in this case is my large intestines, which are no
longer hooked up to my rectum. The sensation they are missing is the pressure
that comes when stool builds up in the colon, which in turn triggers the
sensations of “needing to go”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one or two times a day I get the sensation of “needing to go”. I
logically know that’s an impossibility, but apparently my rectum is not swayed
by logic, so I had to look for alternative methods of getting the sensation to
go away. It turns out there is one way to get it to go away and that’s to go
and sit on the toilet as if I were having a bowl-movement. And I realize, as I
sit here, on the toilet, not having a bowl-movement, that what I’m really
doing in playing “make pretend” for my rectum. And it works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if my rectum will be as grateful as my kids are for all the time I
spent playing “make pretend” with them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">This is another story from my recovery that might be TMI for some people. Read with caution, or skip.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tim O’Reilly on Silicon Valley</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/tim-oreilly-on-silicon-valley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tim O'Reilly on Silicon Valley" /><published>2019-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-08T09:23:32-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/tim-oreilly-on-silicon-valley</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/tim-oreilly-on-silicon-valley">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1540608/the-problem-with-silicon-valleys-obsession-with-blitzscaling-growth/&quot;&gt;The fundamental problem with Silicon Valley’s favorite growth strategy&lt;/a&gt;
is great article by Tim O’Reilly on the fundamental harm Silicon Valley’s
single-minded pursuit of unicorns does to the whole economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">The fundamental problem with Silicon Valley’s favorite growth strategy is great article by Tim O’Reilly on the fundamental harm Silicon Valley’s single-minded pursuit of unicorns does to the whole economy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The real value of a 70% top marginal tax rate</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/the-real-value-of-a-70-top-marginal-tax-rate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The real value of a 70% top marginal tax rate" /><published>2019-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-08T09:38:30-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/the-real-value-of-a-70-top-marginal-tax-rate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/the-real-value-of-a-70-top-marginal-tax-rate">&lt;p&gt;The last time we had a 70% top marginal tax rate in the U.S.
it generated very little revenue. That doesn’t mean it failed,
that means it was doing it’s job, as explained in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.interfluidity.com/v2/7065.html&quot;&gt;The opportunity cost of firm payouts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">The last time we had a 70% top marginal tax rate in the U.S. it generated very little revenue. That doesn’t mean it failed, that means it was doing it’s job, as explained in The opportunity cost of firm payouts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three weeks out</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/3-weeks-out" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three weeks out" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T09:53:34-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/3-weeks-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/02/3-weeks-out">&lt;p&gt;It’s now been close to three weeks since my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened&quot;&gt;emergency surgery&lt;/a&gt; and
I am recoving slowly. As I’ve gotten better I’ve progressed through the three
stages of TV watching:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can’t watch TV, too much activity and sound.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I could sit here and watch David Attenborough for days on end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I watch any more TV my brain is going to melt and flow out through my
ears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, what happened to cooking shows on TV? Remember when they used to just be
someone preparing a recipe? When did they become talk shows? I miss the days
of &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/eK4umRMJlrs&quot;&gt;Justin Wilson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten better enough to actually cook dinner for the family, which is an
incredibly gratifying stage in my return to being a productive human being,
though it is quite a longer process than normal, as I’m still recovering. The
prep for dinner last night was little bouts of activity spread across three
hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean space in fridge for chicken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a nap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spatchcock the chicken and salt it, place in fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rest for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice zucchini and onion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take another nap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it’s slow and steady progress every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">It’s now been close to three weeks since my emergency surgery and I am recoving slowly. As I’ve gotten better I’ve progressed through the three stages of TV watching:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A thing that happened</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thing that happened" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T09:53:34-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/a-thing-that-happened">&lt;p&gt;So here I am on a Tuesday morning, in the bathroom, getting ready for work
while my wife still sleeps. The only context you need for what’s about to
happen next is that my intestines had been a little sore the previous two
days and that last year I found out that I had diverticulosis. The latter
found because when you turn 50 you get a free colonoscopy. I really don’t
think there is a more apt metaphor for turning 50 than a free colonoscopy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;, the rest of this story contains references to urine, feces,
blood, needles, and any number of other unpleasant dinner table topics. If
you are squeamish, or would be unable to look me in the eye the next time we
meet, you should stop reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sitting on the toilet when I get a huge flapping and stabbing pain in my
intestines. This is a pain that is so intense and otherworldly that I’m thrown
off the toilet onto my hands and knees. It is hard to describe this feeling,
but imagine taking a wooden children’s block, you know the ones, with the big
letters and numbers on them in bold colors? So take one of those, attach it to
the head of a 3/8” drill-bit, shove that up your ass, and then turn on the
drill. Yeah, that’s exactly what it felt like. I’m able to crawl a few
feet before calling out to my wife, where she finds me naked in the fetal
position on the cold bathroom tile floor. She asks, and as I can start to
breath again as the pain descends, on a scale from 0 to 10, from a 10 down to
about a 6, I explain what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s start with getting me a pillow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lying on the floor for awhile and having the pain subside down to about
a 4, I get dressed, and get a 2pm doctor’s appointment. The office says they
can and do want to see me soon given the severity of what might be going on,
so I schedule a 2pm appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never make that appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynne is out walking the dog, almost back to the house, when I call her,
“Forget the doctor’s appointment, we need to go to the ER, now!” My pain has
shot back up to an 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pain for next two hours will oscillate between a 4 and an 8. Yes, you heard
that correctly, the next two hours. It will take that long to get me though
the triaging process and into an ER bed and enough tests run that they start
to give me something for the pain. I do get the idea that the doctors don’t
want to mask any pain that might help with a diagnosis, but do you really
think that the difference between me howling incoherently and merely able to
speak and tell them my pain is a 6 is that sharp of a diagnostic tool?
Regardless, I spend the next two hours oscillating between a 4 and an 8, and
anything above a 7 requires chanting the “Litany of Pain”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;Shit. Fuck. Damn.&quot;
&quot;Shit. Fuck. Damn.&quot;
&quot;Fuck. Fuck. Fucking fuckity fuck.&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I promptly did, for an hour, in the ER waiting room lying across a bench
seat. Please note that I understand that your personal “Litany of Pain” may differ,
and may change based on the pain level, for example mine tends to peter out at
a 9 to just gurgling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CT scan comes back with “inflamed diverticulum” and a surgeon appears to
explain that given my pain it’s probably ruptured and that she’d like to
operate, or we could wait awhile and see if antibiotics make a difference in
the pain. I’m not going to jump into any surgery, so I decide to wait, but the
description of what the actual surgery will entail really makes me uneasy. The
plan would be open me up, cut out the offending piece of colon, and route the
end of the now shorter colon into an ostomy. I had no idea the human body was
that flexible, “Hey let’s re-route your butt hole to somewhere in your
abdomen!” seems more like a Zoidberg surgery than an actual procedure, who
knew? Anyway, then the rest of the plan is to wait three months for everything
to heal, and do the reverse surgery, undoing the colonostomy and reconnecting
my colon to my anus. What exactly my anus is supposed to be doing for those
three months is a question I forget to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend the next 24 hours in the hospital with IV antibiotics as my
temperature, white blood cell count, and pain continue to rise. A new CT scan
confirms that I have a ruptured colon: I will not be avoiding surgery. In
fact, they are so alarmed that they take me straight from the CT to the
operating room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about “Versed”, a drug that they give you before surgery so that
you don’t remember any of the horrors that surgery, or surgery prep, or coming
out of surgery entail. It does all that, but apparently it also pretty well
scrambles your brain for some time following the surgery. When I woke up in my
hospital room the doctor was there explaining my status, the surgery, what
they found, and next steps to my wife. Except that my brain was translating
their entire conversation into Kubernetes command line strings (essentially a
kind of programming language). And I’m there taking in as if was completely
normal, like I’m happy I got the surgery at such a cutting edge place that
they’re using Kubernetes to control their surgical procedures. It’s not until
days later in the hospital, in a fleeting instance of lucidity, that I realize
how fucking insane and nonsensical that sounds. So I begin going back over
the things I know and fact checking them. I know, for example, that they have
me up and walking right after surgery and that I take regular walks on that
hospital floor, and as I get better I might be able to go for a walk in the
outside exercise area, which is a small stone-lined plaza in Italy. Wait,
what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the full eight days I spent in the hospital are a little
fuzzy, and I might not be a reliable witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the eight days I had get to past certain milestones, such as peeing on my
own. I never realized how happy you could make a nurse by peeing, which
apparently comes in second place only to how happy you can make a nurse by
producing stool from your stoma. I’m pretty sure I was an infant the last time
that many people were excited by my poop production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am home recovering from colon surgery. It’s like having a new baby, all
the conversations are about pee, poop, and sleeping schedules, except in this
case, I’m the baby. Really it’s all about the gas. Every part of my now
shortened digestive tract is swollen and irritable, so everything produces
gas, and all gas produces discomfort. Which leads me to my three rules of
colon surgery recovery discomfort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s always gas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walking fixes everything. (See #1).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unless maybe you’re hungry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I walk, and I walk, and I walk. In the house though, because it has been
either too cold outside, or drenching rain. So I walk up and down the upstairs
hall, or loop-de-loops around the furniture downstairs, and I belch, and I
belch, and I belch. That’s apparently yet another thing that makes nurses
happy; I would be doing one of my regular walks in the hospital wing and let out
one of those deep, loud belches that start at your toes, and a cheer would
rise from the nurses station every time. Nurses are weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just two days home from the hospital at this point, with another two weeks
of recovery at least before I can return to anything resembling a normal life,
except for the shadow of the reversal surgery hanging out there three months
from now. Thanks for reading this far, as I know that writing it has certainly
helped me process my adventure to date. Many thanks to family, friends, and
co-workers for all their support, it means a huge amount to me and Lynne. Oh
yeah, did I mention that Lynne had a sinus infection through all this, she’s
been an amazing trooper, my rock, and I wouldn’t have made it through without
her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">So here I am on a Tuesday morning, in the bathroom, getting ready for work while my wife still sleeps. The only context you need for what’s about to happen next is that my intestines had been a little sore the previous two days and that last year I found out that I had diverticulosis. The latter found because when you turn 50 you get a free colonoscopy. I really don’t think there is a more apt metaphor for turning 50 than a free colonoscopy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nine steps for Facebook</title><link href="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nine steps for Facebook" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T16:37:58-05:00</updated><id>https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bitworking.org/news/2019/01/nine-steps-for-facebook">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/22/restructure-facebook-ftc-regulate-9-steps-now&quot;&gt;Facebook must be restructured. The FTC should take these nine steps now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was published back in March of 2018, but it’s still a good list of things
that should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Gregorio</name></author><summary type="html">Facebook must be restructured. The FTC should take these nine steps now</summary></entry></feed>